<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Who is Alex Larioza?!</title>
    <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Who is Alex Larioza?!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://alexlarioza.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cozy Grove</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cozygrove/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cozygrove/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Cozy Grove, a life-sim game about camping on a haunted, ever-changing island. As a Spirit Scout, you&#39;ll wander the island&#39;s forest each day, finding new hidden secrets and helping soothe the local ghosts. With a little time and a lot of crafting, you&#39;ll bring color and joy back to Cozy Grove!
Role  Lead Porting Engineer for Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and PS4  Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Collaborated with developers to make a console-friendly experience Integrated console APIs (save data, achievements, user management, etc) Ensured game passed all console certification requirements  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space Otter Charlie</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/spaceottercharlie/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/spaceottercharlie/</guid>
      <description>With humanity gone, it’s up to the otters to save animal-kind from an inhospitable Earth. Join Charlie and his ragtag crew of critters on a daring mission through Otter Space as they search for a new planet to call home. Explore derelict space stations, battle unhinged robots, and enjoy some otterly terrific puns as you jump, float, and fly through over a dozen levels of furry fun.
Role  Lead Porting Engineer for Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, PS4, and Amazon Luna  Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Collaborated with developers to make a console-friendly experience Optimized graphics and code to run smoothly on consoles Integrated console APIs (save data, achievements, user management, etc) Ensured game passed all console certification requirements  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fracter</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/fracter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/fracter/</guid>
      <description>FRACTER is an emotive, isometric puzzle adventure game set in a mysterious labyrinth of glowing black architecture. The game follows a veiled young hero who has set out on a perilous quest to dispel the darkness within. Players must explore this world of shadows, discover secrets hidden in the dark, and outsmart ominous creatures while solving each meticulously designed puzzle using their only force against darkness: light. Dramatic landscapes in shades of gray, an eerie ambient soundtrack and a poetic, self-reflective narrative await you on this emotional journey restoring light to a darkened world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#Funtime</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/funtime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/funtime/</guid>
      <description>#Funtime is an explosive twin-stick shooter where shooting isn&#39;t your only weapon. #Funtime combines traditional twin-stick shooting with a unique coloring mechanic. Earn bonus points by coloring the playing field and exploding enemies that cross your path. Persistent ship upgrades allow for lengthier runs filled with even more mayhem. Fast and fun gameplay will have you coming back again and again.
Role  Lead Porting Engineer for Nintendo Switch, Xbox One, and PS4  Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Collaborated with developer to make a console-friendly experience Optimized graphics and code to run smoothly on consoles Integrated console APIs (save data, achievements, user management, etc) Ensured game passed all console certification requirements  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IronWriter</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/ironwriter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/ironwriter/</guid>
      <description>IronWriter is an open-source writing tool for solo playthroughs of the free tabletop RPG Ironsworn. Focus on writing your story and let IronWriter automatically manage your character sheet.
Role Designer and Programmer
Technologies  HTML, CSS, and Javascript  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cast Your Vote</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cyv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cyv/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s just a few weeks until Election Day, are you ready? In our completely reimagined, Cast Your Vote, you&#39;ll discover what it takes to become an informed voter - from knowing where you stand on important issues to uncovering what you need to know about candidates.
Role  Lead Engineer through Alpha phase Support Engineer through Beta phase  Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic External content management system via Airtable Developed procedural candidate generation Created Designer friendly tools for content generation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race to Ratify</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/ratify/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/ratify/</guid>
      <description>Race to Ratify drops you into 1787, where the ink is still drying on the new Constitution. Will it become the law of the land or will it fall into the dustbin of history? The fate of the young nation is in your hands! Dive deep into the heated national debate over the future of a radical new plan for American government. Travel across the 13 states to hear from a diverse and opinionated cast of characters and use what you have learned to influence others through the social media of the time&amp;hellip; pamphlets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration Nation</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/immigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/immigration/</guid>
      <description>Do you know how people become citizens of the United States? In Immigration Nation, you&#39;ll find out as you guide newcomers along their path to citizenship.
Role Lead Engineer
Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic External content management system for client Content localization system Path resolution system for boats in puzzle mode  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodoku</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/nodoku/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/nodoku/</guid>
      <description>Nodoku offers a brain-bending new way to play with numbers, kill time, and stay sharp. Use your mathematical super powers to discover additive sequences and solve clean, colorful, free-form line puzzles.
Snappy animations and transitions make this addictive, compulsively playable game ideal for quick plays on the bus or for marathon sessions while you binge Netflix. With 100+ handcrafted, deceptively simple levels, Nodoku is easy to learn, but tricky to master.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooptris</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cooptris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cooptris/</guid>
      <description>Cooptris is a cooperative Tetris clone. Same rules as the original: don&#39;t let blocks reach the top of the screen! Both players share the same hold space which is useful for trading pieces. Your current piece can get in the way of the other player, so good communication is required! This was a small project with the goal to make a game with PICO-8.
Role Programming, design, and art
Technologies  PICO-8  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Games Right Meow</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/gamesrightmeow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/gamesrightmeow/</guid>
      <description>Games Right Meow is the customer-facing company for all of my commercial games.
Role Founder
Key Responsibilities  Designed and built company Run playtests to gather feedback Attend local events to exhibit games Design and program games  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Survived By</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/survivedby/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/survivedby/</guid>
      <description>Survived By is a free-to-play MMO bullet-hell game where permadeath is just the beginning. Every time you die, you’re survived by a new descendant who carries a small part of your legacy with them.
Team up with hundreds of survivors as you shoot your way through hordes of Chimera, explore dungeons, collect loot, craft gear and of course… die. Again, and again. Who will you be survived by…?
Role Gameplay and UI Programmer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counties Work</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/counties/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/counties/</guid>
      <description>Want to try your hand at running your own county government? In Counties Work, you can! Stay on top of resident requests as you develop the local community, make important budgeting decisions and solve crises that pop up along the way.
Role Lead Engineer
Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic External content management system for client Procedural bobble generator (appearance and needs) Game logic  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executive Command</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/excom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/excom/</guid>
      <description>Running for the presidency isn’t easy! Manage your very own presidential campaign by strategically raising funds, polling voters, launching media campaigns, and making personal appearances.
Role Lead Engineer
Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic External content management system for client Highly configurable and designer friendly event system Isometric pathfinding  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubbles</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/bubbles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/bubbles/</guid>
      <description>This game is bursting with learning! Your little ones will pop their way into a whimsical world to learn letter sounds, phonics, and new words! Compatible with the Square Panda Playset, children love playtime as they use Square Panda smart letters to hear letter sounds and spell out new words. The more letters the child puts in the Playset, the more bubbles they get to pop! As your child pops bubbles they hear phonemic sounds and discover what real words are hiding behind the world of bubbles!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win the White House</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/wtwh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/wtwh/</guid>
      <description>Running for the presidency isn’t easy! In Win the White House, you get to manage your very own presidential campaign by strategically raising funds, polling voters, launching media campaigns, and making personal appearances. Keep a close eye on the map as you battle over electoral votes and popular support.
Role Support Engineer
Technologies  Unity  Key Responsibilities  Optimized game to run on min spec device  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animobile</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/animobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/animobile/</guid>
      <description>Animobile Adventures is a game where players drive around exploring habitats and to learn about the animals that live within them. We wanted to teach players how we can learn from animals to solve everyday problems. Throughout the course of the game players earn traits that can be used to transform the Animobile to overcome challenges they encounter. The team was also given with the opportunity to work with Make-A-Wish and grant Abby Mank’s wish of being immortalized in a video game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supercar Showdown</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/supercar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/supercar/</guid>
      <description>Supercar Showdown is a top-down racing game with a focus on controlled drifting that takes inspiration from Micro Machines and Hot Wheels. In single player mode, the player is pitted against AI racers which develop rivalries over the course of the game. The game also features an async multiplayer mode allowing players to compete with others all over the world.
Role Gameplay and UI Programmer
Technologies  Flash  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic Vehicle upgrade system Opponent racing and drifting AI  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Soccer</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/minisoccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/minisoccer/</guid>
      <description>You don&#39;t have to be a soccer expert to play MiniSoccer - just be ready to have fun! Challenge live players in real-time multiplayer matches with up to 6 people. Create a private room and play with your friends, or join a random match and make new ones. Don&#39;t want to be stuck in the goal? Set an AI goalkeeper so you&#39;re free to sprint to the ball and score! Set time or score limits and play to your heart&#39;s content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caved In 2</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cavedin2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cavedin2/</guid>
      <description>Dig your way through treacherous caverns while saving damsels in distress in this sequel to the original Caved In. The goal of the game is to descend as deep as you can while rescuing damsels and collecting treasures. As you dig, you weaken the integrity of the level. The lower the integrity, the more often cave ins occur! Special thanks to Chris Sinnott for the theme song and sound effects!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full Auto Mayhem</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/fullauto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/fullauto/</guid>
      <description>Full Auto Mayhem is a racing-combat hybrid that features three game modes - Race, Time Attack, and Elimination. Each track has it&#39;s own unique hazards and hidden shortcuts. Players earn components for their car from 8 base weapons and 6 base car parts with randomly generated stats.
Role Gameplay and UI Programmer
Technologies  Flash  Key Responsibilities  Implement UI and game logic Procedurally generated component system Opponent AI  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smash Palace</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/smash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/smash/</guid>
      <description>Smash Palace was a significant milestone in my career as it was the first commercial game that I contributed to. During the development of this project I was in charge of general gameplay programming and AI. The goal of the game is to smash into opponents and do as much damage as you can (preferably until they explode). If you&#39;re the last car running, you&#39;ve survived the round! Between rounds you can spend your hard earned cash on upgrades for your garage full of cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infested Space</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/infestedspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/infestedspace/</guid>
      <description>Your crew is dead. The ship is infested. All you have is a blaster and a flashlight. Can you make it out alive? Infested Space originally started as a Ludum Dare idea, but I ended up dropping out of the jam. Then in July &amp;lsquo;12 I decided to revisit the idea as a short, one-week summer project. I ended up spending about two months on the project. The gameplay focuses on exploration and staying alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanonaut</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/nanonaut/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/nanonaut/</guid>
      <description>Nanonaut was originally created for the #23 Ludum Dare &amp;lsquo;Tiny Planet&amp;rsquo; as a jam entry. I worked with three other people to create this game - Chris Sinnott , Thomas Jackson, and Travis Lucia. It was quite an ambitious project for such a small time period, yet we still ended up with a great game. Nanonaut is a game of exploration and adventure within a randomly generated world of tiny planets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sopoids</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/sopoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/sopoids/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the game is to fend off 7 waves of SOPA ship. Every time a ship attacks the earth, a letter in the word freedom is censored. Once the whole word is censored, it is game over. There are three different ship types: one flies straight at the earth, another follows and shoots the player, and the other sieges the earth from afar. For every 7 SOPA ships you destroy, another supporter (another fighter) will join your cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caved In</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cavedin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/cavedin/</guid>
      <description>Caved In was originally made for Ludum Dare #21 for the theme &amp;lsquo;escape&amp;rsquo;. The core concept behind this game was inspired by Minecraft and Terraria. This post compo version contains a compass to aide the player with finding the ladder as well as some bug fixes. The goal of the game is to dig your way out five levels of dirt and find the ladder. Each level is randomly generated and filled with water, lava, treasure, and a damsel that needs saving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spacejunk</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/spacejunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/spacejunk/</guid>
      <description>There are a total of 24 waves that the player must complete in order to finish the game. Normal waves consist of blasting incoming garbage and asteroids in order to obtain spacedust. Spacedust is then used to purchase upgrades for the planet between each wave. Every three waves a boss planet appears; each unique and requires a different strategy to defeat. Special thanks to Chris Sinnott for the theme song!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expelliarmus</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/expelliarmus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/expelliarmus/</guid>
      <description>Expelliarmus is a short experimental game I created in a few hours. Type out the words that appear at the top of the screen faster than the AI opponent in order to cast a spell. Spells do damage based on the length of the spell. The first wizard to reach zero health loses! Special thanks to Chris Sinnott for the theme song!
Role Programming, design, and art
Technologies  Flash  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torch</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/torch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/torch/</guid>
      <description>Torch was originally created for Ludum Dare #20 for the theme &amp;lsquo;It&#39;s dangerous to go alone; take this!&#39;. This is the post compo version which features some level fixes and graphical enhancements. The light/torch concept was inspired by Amnesia. There is a single level that the player must traverse and rescue the girl. Avoid traps and creatures that steal your torch. If you are in the darkness for too long you will be sent back to the most recent checkpoint.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love is in the Air</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/loveisintheair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/loveisintheair/</guid>
      <description>Love in the Air was created in 48 hours for Valentine&#39;s Day. It lacks much polish, but overall turned out quite well for my first Flash game! Each wave, there are a set number of hearts that travel towards the player. They must all be shot down with your limited number of missiles. This game was heavily inspired by the gaming classic, Missile Command.
Role Programming, design, and art
Technologies  Flash  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voyage of Discovery</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/voyageofdiscovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/projects/voyageofdiscovery/</guid>
      <description>Voyage of Discovery was created during the #19 Ludum Dare &amp;lsquo;Discovery&#39;. This was the first game I ever completed and also my first Ludum Dare. Granted, it was a bit ambitious for a first project, but hey, I finished it! The goal of the game is to colonize all of the islands while managing your supplies and surviving pirate attacks.
Role Programming, design, and art
Technologies  Gamemaker  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>