<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Who is Alex Larioza?!</title>
    <link>http://alexlarioza.com/categories/news/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Who is Alex Larioza?!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016 Alex Larioza</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://alexlarioza.com/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>2014: Year In Review</title>
      <link>http://alexlarioza.com/blog/2014yearinreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://alexlarioza.com/blog/2014yearinreview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even after spending a few days attempting to transcribe my feelings and emotions, I still feel that this post doesn’t even come close to conveying how important this year has been to me. I traveled to two states, graduated from college, met a plethora of new people, hiked a 13-mile trail, visited the beautiful parks of Big Sur and Muir Woods, saw Linkin Park in concert, and finished two commercial games…just to name a few. It was an epic year of exploration, personal growth, and self discovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I think my decision to accept a job at Filament Games has been the most pivotal. While I’m quite excited to meet my new coworkers and create some awesome games, I’m also thrilled about moving to the mid-west and gaining the independence I’ve sought after for so long. It’s unfortunate that such a great opportunity also means that I have to leave behind my friends and family. No combination of words could describe how much I appreciate them. I am forever in debt for all of their love and support; I wouldn’t be who I am today without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I learned many things this year I think the most import thing was that every choice you make should take you a step closer to your dreams, not away from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, &lt;em&gt;follow your heart and fuck the rest&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>